<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning on X-Ray Science Division Coffee Talk Announcements</title>
    <link>https://tekinbicer.github.io/xsd-coffee-talks/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine learning on X-Ray Science Division Coffee Talk Announcements</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tekinbicer.github.io/xsd-coffee-talks/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing X-ray Tomography using Artificial Intelligence (TomoGAN)</title>
      <link>https://tekinbicer.github.io/xsd-coffee-talks/posts/20200302_zhengchun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tekinbicer.github.io/xsd-coffee-talks/posts/20200302_zhengchun/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We apply artificial intelligence techniques to advance X-ray tomography imaging experiments at synchrotron light sources, in both post processing and online (or near real-time streaming) processing scenarios. We also explore its applicability in practical experiment configurations, for example in scenarios in which a deep learning model is trained on a supercomputer but executed for inference on an edge computing device (e.g., Google edge TPU, NVIDIA Jetson). Specifically, we share three aspects of deep learning for X-ray tomography in this talks: (1) TomoGAN, a denoising technique based on generative adversarial networks, for improving the quality of reconstructed images in low-dose imaging conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-fidelity geometry generation from CT data using convolutional neural networks</title>
      <link>https://tekinbicer.github.io/xsd-coffee-talks/posts/prev-017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tekinbicer.github.io/xsd-coffee-talks/posts/prev-017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The X-ray Fuel Spray research at Argonne National Laboratory is aimed at utilizing synchrotron X-ray diagnostics for providing insights into automotive fuel injection. One important task is to generate high-fidelity geometries or iso-surfaces of steel fuel injector nozzles from X-ray Computed Tomography measurements, to be used as inputs to realistic CFD simulations of fuel injector flow. These fuel nozzles contain 3D features between 5 - 500 micron and are imaged at a pixel resolution of 1 micron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview of super-resolution technique for X-ray imaging</title>
      <link>https://tekinbicer.github.io/xsd-coffee-talks/posts/prev-015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tekinbicer.github.io/xsd-coffee-talks/posts/prev-015/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In the past, image scale-up/super-resolution task was completed by making use of either interpolation method or the sparse coding based dictionary learning method. However, in the recent times, the popularity of machine learning tools such as neural networks to solve a wide range of imaging problems meant that even the super-resolution problem was resolved using the Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs). In this talk, we will present some of the popular CNN-architectures that are relevant to scale-up the X-ray images.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>